A Guide to the Buckhorn Coal Company Records 1880-1961
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Buckhorn Coal Company Records 1880-1961
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1984-175
1.2 cu. ft, 3 boxes, 2 oversize folders
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Buckhorn Coal Company owned and operated coal lands in Russell and Buchanan Counties, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The Buckhorn Coal Company records consists of 25 blueprints, eleven ledgers, and one deed of lease. The small collection of blueprints detail the coal lands and tunnels of Buckhorn Coal Company, as well as the prospectus and abstracts of lease arrangements. Accompanying the blueprints are eleven comprehensive ledgers which consist of stock transfers, roster of Buckhorn Coal Company stockholders, and cash books.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by size.
Contents List
- Buckhorn Coal Company Records 1880-1961
  - Ledger, list of investors, 126 p. 1888-1917 (Box 1)
  - Stock ledger, list of stockholders, 103 p. 1890-91 (Box 1)
  - Stock ledger, 185 p. 1891-1954 (Box 1)
  - Lease book, list of lessees, 75 p. 1917-20 (Box 1)
  - Ledger - preferred stockholders and preferred dividends, 83 p. 1917-22 (Box 1)
  - Cash book, 196 p. 1918-41 (Box 1)
  - Cash book, 150 p. 1944-61 (Box 1)
  - Stock ledger, list of stockholders, 91 p. 1880-89 (Box 2)
  - Cash book, 324 p. 1888-95 (Box 2)
  - Wakenva Coal Co. Blueprint, Garden Operation, Drill, VA Oct. 16, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Deed of lease of the Buckhorn Coal Co. 1950-58 (Box 2)
  - Meadows Coal Co. Blueprint, Mine 11, Swords Creek, VA (Box 2)
  - Banner Raven Coal Co., mine workings in the Upper Banner Seam, Drill, VA (Box 2)
  - Unititled blueprint n.d. (Box 2)
  - Large cash book, 150 p. 1918-43 (Box 3)
  - Large cash book, 239 p. 1918-46 (Box 3)
  - Garden Coal Co. blueprint, workings in the Widow Kennedy seam, Drill, VA (Box 3)
  - Banner Raven Coal Corp. blueprint, projected mine workings in the Upper Banner seam, Drill, VA (Box 3)
  - Garden Coal Co., mine map of Kennedy seam, Drill VA September 27, 1918 (Oversize 1)
  - Laurel Coal Co., mine map of Russell County, VA October 15, 1918 (Oversize 1)
  - Banner Raven Coal Corp., mine working in the upper banner seam, Drill, VA (3 blueprints) (Oversize 1)
  - Appalachian Electric Power Co., coal creek west circle October 19, 1936 (Oversize 2)
  - Tazewell Coal & Iron Co., map of coal lands in Russell County, VA (Oversize 2)
  - Buckhorn Coal Co., map of mines in the Widow Kennedy seam (7 blueprints) (Oversize 2)
  - Buckhorn Coal Co., map showing property south of 1st lease (Oversize 2)
  - Buckhorn Coal Co., map of Upper Banner mines (2 blueprints) (Oversize 2)